

# **Contacts**

919691346

luismiguelcsimoes@gmail.com

luismcs.github.io / github.com/Luismcs

in www.linkedin.com/in/luis-simoesdeveloper/

Porto, Portugal

# **Digital Skills**

Java 21

Spring Framework

PHP

Laravel

C#

SQL,

GIT & Github

HTML, CSS, Javascript

### **Soft Skills**

Organized

**Teamwork** 

**Taking Notes** 

# Languages

Portuguese (native)

English (advanced)

# Luís Simões

# BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I am an enthusiast for technology, with a strong passion for learning and a commitment to continuous improvement mostly in Backend Development. Adaptable, disciplined, and growth-oriented, I thrive in challenging software development environments, contributing effectively to team success while expanding my expertise.

# **Experience**

09/2024 - 11/2024

Junior Java Developer at HumanIT Digital Consulting (Internship)

- Completed a Java Academy focused on backend development with Java 21 and Spring Framework, enhancing technical and practical skills.
- Designed and implemented multiple backend projects, including APIs and microservices, applying best practices in software development.
- Collaborated closely with a Senior Developer, receiving mentorship on code quality, debugging, and clean architecture.
- Completed courses on project management methodologies, such as Scrum, and participated in technical English training sessions, enhancing the ability to communicate in professional environments.

### 12/2020 - 06/2021

IT Team member at Escola Secundária da Boa Nova (Internship)

- Maintained IT school equipment.
- Developed a website for the course in Wix.

# **Projects**

05/2024 - 07/2024

#### Qualitask

- Technologies: Laravel, Blade, MySQL, Javascript, AWS
- Developed a solution for attendance tracking and management of schedules, shifts, absences, and vacations.
- Implemented data import/export functionalities and metrics generation in dashboards.

# 11/2024- Still going

# **Salary Management Portal**

- Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Docker
- Developed a microservices platform for managing collaborators, salaries, and report export using RabbitMQ.
- Features include JWT authentication, dashboards, and automated email report delivery.

# **Education**

# 06/2023 - 11/2024

# **Technical Course in Computer Management and Programming**

# Systems (Level 5)- ATEC Academia de Formação

- Programming Languages: C#,C++.
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, PHP, Laravel.
- Database: SQL, SQL Server.
- Operative Systems: Windows 2019 Server, Linux Debian.
- Networking: Cisco Packet Tracer.
- Other: Git, GitHub, APIs.
- Website: www.atec.pt

### 09/2018 - 06/2021

#### **Technical Course in Computer Management and Programming**

# Systems (Level 4)- Escola Secundária da Boa Nova

- Programming Languages: C++, Java.
- Web Development: HTML.
- Database: MySQL.